Podcasting 2.0 for July 25th,
2025, episode 228, Tokenless.
Hello, everybody.
Oh, oh, what's happening?
We're back after a two-week
hiatus, hanging out,
walking through woods
aimlessly, unconnected.
It is time once again for Podcasting 2.0,
where we find out what's really going
on in podcasting, what happened,
what's happening now, what is
happening very soon, all the dirt,
all the down, and the dirty.
We are, in fact, the only
boardroom that doesn't have
a private meeting room
at Podcast Movement.
I'm Adam Curry here in the heart of
the Texas Hill Country and in Alabama.
The man who thinks freemium is
something you clean your oven with.
Say hello to my friend on the other
end, the one, the only, Mr. Dave Jones.
Oh, well, did you see
Spurlock, what he just posted?
Just now?
Yeah, on the sofa.
I need to set up a trigger whenever
Spurlock posts it has to text me because he
truly is one of the main
reasons I check multiple
times a day just to see
what Spurlock does.
I thought that was from me.
I'm sorry.
Yes.
Latest July stats from Power.
Is that what we're looking at?
Oh, Godcaster.
What?
Yeah, we're neck and neck with Dogcatcher.
The Godcaster and Dogcatcher.
Yeah.
It's us.
We have the same percentage
of OP3 downloads as LinkedIn.
Did you?
I didn't even know LinkedIn did podcast.
But hold on.
We're ahead of Deezer.
And we're also ahead of Chromecast device.
Chromecast device.
Whatever that is.
Now, by coincidence, I listened to
Power on the Godcaster this morning.
You did too?
Yeah.
Oh, on Godcaster.
You guys know.
Okay.
I did not listen to it on Godcaster.
So that 0.1% was me.
It's all you.
It's all me, baby.
I am 0.1%.
Yeah.
If I got, if I should switch
over and start using it,
start listening to Power on Godcaster,
and then I could bump us up to 0.2%.
Woo!
So we haven't actually
made the announcement yet.
And I'll just tell the
backstory of that to people.
First of all, I want to
share a tip with everybody.
A little tip.
Just a tip.
A little tip of the day.
If you happen to live
kind of in a rural area
and you have well water like myself, and
you know, it does happen
that the person who
built the home put kind of a cheapo water
softener system in, one that
is basically not serviceable.
So, you know, so it's got all this,
you know, all this gunk going on.
And so my man, Randall, by the way, host
of the Shaman, the Whiskey Shaman podcast.
Oh, nice.
Okay.
Shout out.
Yeah.
Shout out to Whiskey Shaman.
He says, nah, well, I mean, you
can better just get a new one.
All right, let's get a new one.
So he says, hey.
And he says, I just got a cancellation.
I can come by now.
Okay, perfect.
He comes by.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, not at all.
No, much, much.
Thank goodness.
No.
But he'd already, he already
came over to look at it.
And so he's installing.
But memo to self, when your guy,
Randall, your Whiskey Shaman,
when he is installing your
water softener, do not, I repeat, do not
poop because you will not have any water.
Wait, what?
Yeah, I went to the.
Oh, to wash the poop down.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah.
So it's not safe in there, babe.
Don't go in there.
You dropped a bomb and left it.
I left it for somebody to step on.
I left a major bomb.
Oh, man.
That's a horrible thing to do.
At least, you know, you were
talking, I think it was,
was it John that was talking about,
this has been a while back on NA, he was
talking about the poop shelf in the toilet.
Oh, yeah.
The Dutch poop shelf.
Oh, okay.
It was you.
Yeah.
The Russians have that too.
Oh, really?
Every, every toilet in
Moscow has a poop shelf.
Yeah.
And you know the history of it, right?
I'm right.
I mean, the only thing I can
think of is that you can,
it's so that you can check out your
poop and see if there's like
worms in it or something.
Yes.
Early on when the only buildings
that had toilets were hospitals,
but everyone else was just
pooping in the canal or whatever
they did back in the day.
Fun.
That's fun.
And so the hospitals had a little shelf
in there exactly for that reason.
So they can, okay, let me
go check and yeah, yeah,
it looks like you're good or whatever,
you know, just check the poop.
And it was so bizarre to poop on a shelf.
Yeah.
Pooping on a shelf.
And that became the, the main toilet maker,
just continue to make those forever.
And the Dutch, I think
they secretly enjoy it.
It's, it makes for when the poop
does not go under the water,
when it just sits on the
shelf, it makes for a
very stinky bathroom.
It is, it is a very odiferous and pungent
experience to be in that bathroom.
Interesting.
And I really don't want to just
turn around and check it out.
I mean, I'd, I'd rather just
flush that thing right now.
Well, interestingly enough, you know,
when I was visiting my
daughter in Rotterdam, uh,
was it April, I think.
And, uh, and you know, I didn't met all,
she's still be 35 in August
and all of her friends
are kind of the same age and they're,
uh, they're the, the millennials,
you know, they're the older millennials.
They're a cool bunch.
They're kind of getting their
lives together, starting families.
And, uh, and Christina says to
me, dad, dad, dad, you gotta get,
you gotta be getting our
league to your league.
Yeah.
You gotta get this app.
It is the, the poop map app.
Is that for how, for the
homeless pooping on the streets?
No, no, no, no.
You register your poop and
then you, and you just, yeah.
And you get badges and
all kinds of awards.
You know, like, um, I
pooped on the airplane.
I got like a special award
for over 10,000 feet.
Yes.
This is not.
And we're in a league.
And so we have, we're in a,
we're in a competitive league,
but the thing about it is I know my
daughter's alive, you know, cause kids,
they don't, they don't text you every day.
I'm like, let me check in the poop app.
She poops.
Okay.
She's alive.
So there you go.
There you go.
If she ever gets constipated for a
couple of weeks, you're going to be,
you're a little like, baby, are you okay?
I mean, and they actually got
a prop from like, Christina,
your dad is an excellent
addition to our league.
It must be his radio background.
Cause you know, I'm, I'm making up
all kinds of, um, um, you know,
all kinds of what is
the analogies, you know, when you poop,
you have to describe it in a fun way.
All right.
There we are, everybody.
Yes.
You also put, I mean, as a DJ, you
also have to learn to poop on command.
Oh yeah.
Oh, either that or you're holding it.
You're either pooping on
command or you're holding it.
I am as, as a pilot.
I mean, this, uh, I
have, I am well-trained.
I'm well-trained.
So we've been working
on, uh, uh, Godcasters.
Everybody knows for a long time, we
can go into that in some detail, uh,
because now the app is out.
We, uh, here's what happened.
We, we were thinking on, we were about
ready to go for what, uh, Paul, uh,
our app, our app developer
calls an, uh, an open beta,
which basically means you
put it in the app store
and you say, this is beta.
Yeah.
It just has the word beta in the title.
Cause we had to close beta
for a while, which was cool.
And of course he's developed, um,
the, uh, he's developed both for, uh,
Android and iOS and it's full on native.
And here's the, here's the kicker, 100%
Android auto and CarPlay compatible,
but not just, you know,
like, Oh, it works.
No.
I mean, it's awesome.
I mean, everything, the tabs, you
got four levels deep, you know,
all kinds of amazing stuff.
So it's a real automobile experience.
Yeah.
Paul did a great job.
Um, you know, when you
first fired up, it, uh,
it looks for stations and
stations can be radio stations.
Stations can be podcast networks that
have a live stream, can be a church,
a ministry, and it automatically
finds those for you and you can
follow stations and then follow programs.
It's, I mean, it's, it's, I'm, I think
it's awesome app, but then we weren't,
we're kind of like you were in the
woods for a week and like, well,
we definitely don't want to do
anything until Dave's back,
you know, because thank you.
Thank you.
It's like, we did just because it still
runs off of all of the API stuff.
And, um, and then when I got back,
when I got back and got service, I,
my signal like synced up and it was like,
you have 175 unread signal messages.
I was like, Oh God, I'll
never be able to understand.
Yeah.
So what happened was, uh, last
Sunday, um, was it Sunday?
Uh, no, it was, it was, uh, 10 days ago.
I think all of a sudden I get a message
from Glenn Beck, like, Hey Adam,
it's been two years.
Can you come on?
Can you come on the 29th?
Which I'm going to be in Florida, by the
way, no, no board meeting next week.
Sorry.
Um, uh, and that'll be it though for
the most of the rest of the year.
Um, uh, or the 22nd, which, you
know, was literally a few days away.
I'm like, Oh man, I can't believe this.
What an opportunity to talk about
the Godcaster, the app's not ready.
I ping Paul is like, no, it's ready.
It's good.
We can do it.
I can just press the button.
We're good to go.
Shoo.
Yeah, exactly.
And so I still was like, Nope, we're
waiting for Dave to come back.
Dave has to give a thumbs up.
We're not doing anything,
uh, but it worked out.
They worked out.
It worked out real nice.
And, uh, I think that episode out
yet for blaze subscribers, it's out.
I think, uh, on the RSS as,
as, as the producer told me,
it'll be RSS and everywhere.
On Saturday.
I kind of liked how she said that
it'll be RSS and everywhere,
which I think means YouTube, YouTube.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
RSS and everywhere.
And they release audio and,
uh, and video versions.
Uh, and I guess some people
are already watching.
He brought it, Beck brought
it up within 10 minutes.
I'm like, okay, yeah.
I said, okay, let me,
let's dive in, shall we?
Um, so we were just looking
for, we just want a,
a sizable group for the open beta test.
So that should probably work.
Hoping.
Freemium.
What do you mean?
See Brooklyn.
Oh, it's not freemium.
You don't have to pay for it.
No, there's no freemium.
Yeah.
I should explain the
app is completely free.
No algo's, no ads, no inserts,
no banners flying everywhere.
What this app does is it,
it's a place for radio stations to
use the Godcaster backend, which
means they can put their
podcasts and their live
over the air streams into a
single, uh, a single place.
Um, uh, people aren't leaving
their radio stations.
It's basically, I look at this way.
We give everyone who wants
to be in the Godcaster,
they get a customized
podcast player, a podcast
app that they control.
It's very much like the
Rachel Maddow thing that
we talked about a long time ago where,
you know, have, have an
opinion of your collection.
And so people follow the station.
They automatically follow
the shows that are in there.
And then we added this one cool
thing, which is, um, you, so you,
you load up your, your,
your digital station with podcasts
and then you click, make the,
turn this into a stream
and it turns into a live stream.
And when you're listening to it
in the Godcaster app, you know,
if you check the stream, they'll
just pop in somewhere.
It's, it's that, um, uh, serendipity
that we were talking about with, um,
what's our buddy's name there from, uh,
Tommy, Tom, Tom Webster, Tom Webster.
Yeah.
So it's, it's exactly that it's the serendipity
of just hitting different channels.
Oh, what's this?
Oh, that's interesting.
And then if you want to listen to
the podcast, that episode or more,
you just hit details.
It says view program,
and it takes you right from the
live stream to the episodes and you
can start it over there.
You can add it to your queue.
You can listen to a different one
and all of this is passed through.
So, so everything downloads still go
directly to the hosts and everything.
As you can see, it shows
up as Godcaster with 0.1%.
Yeah.
It's a different kind of podcast app.
It's you, because the whole point
of, of Godcaster as a product is to,
is to keep the radio station
as the center of the universe.
And it's, you know, it's to, it's to help.
I mean, our, you know, our, our goal is
to help radio stations and churches too,
or whoever else wants to do anything,
but it's primarily, you know,
radio stations and ministries and
stuff to make the digital transition
to podcast on demand first,
but it still drives everything
back to the station.
So every, the station is still sort
of the center of the universe.
So it's not a, you know, whereas like in
the I heart app or something like that,
you know, that's a radio that
has a radio centric feel to it.
But as soon as you tap on some
show, you're, you're gone.
The station is lost.
Right.
You have no idea that
like you could enter the
I heart app through your
local radio station,
but pretty quickly you're
just out of that now and you,
and you don't have any connection
back to that station.
So they really don't, they really don't
get any benefit out of it, you know?
So that, that's really kind of where
we're, you know, the focus was.
And it gives radio stations
the opportunity to
promote content they don't have on their
over the air stream.
In fact, there's one station who he,
they're they don't run Chip
Ingram over the air, but
they have him in their, in their Godcaster
and the Chip Ingram people love it.
And of course we have, um,
I think the two important things
to mention because we have
a controlled environment.
So we track plays and all of this stuff.
So, uh, someone who's
running a Godcaster station,
they can really make choices based
upon actual information.
Um, and along with that, we
surface the funding tag.
This is probably one of
the first podcast oriented
apps that really has big donate buttons
everywhere, which by the way,
adheres to the full standards.
So if you put in your funding
tag, support the show,
the button changes to support the show.
And then you tap that
and then it takes you,
it pops you out to the
donation page for that
program or the station.
And the cool thing is that the station,
they get a, uh, a tick in their,
in their dashboard, knowing that
someone clicked on the funding tag for
a different program and
the program producers,
they can also, we're still, we
haven't opened that up fully yet.
They can get their own
producer login and they can
see exactly what stations
they get stats for all
the stations they're on and they
have all the referral codes.
They know exactly where donations
came from, from which station,
because in a Christian radio
and, and this flows through to,
this will flow through to churches
and ministries, uh, having
a revenue share deal is very normal.
I mean, this goes on all the time.
So you put, uh, X state X
program on your station.
If they get a, a donation, they're
supposed to say, Hey, we got a donation.
It came from your station.
Um, here's 20% or whatever the deal is.
Um, which I think is a really cool model.
Of course, it's been broken
for 40 years because
the only way the program
producer knows is if
someone actually checked the box.
Yeah, I heard you on KHCB
or worse or an interview,
if someone calls and
donates over the phone,
like sometimes they forget to
ask, where'd you hear about us?
So now that's all digitally managed.
And that's like, you know,
this blowing people's minds,
like it wasn't all that hard to fix.
So, um, the funding tag is just
front and center along with, uh,
the lit tag, because you can
also follow the station with an
RSS feed in your own podcast app.
If you want, everything flows
right through, uh, I mean,
we really put podcasting 2.0 to
work in this and there's
still a lot to do, obviously.
Um, you know, it's just tons and tons of
stuff to do, but we're also, you know,
we got live clients at the same time.
So it's, it's like walking a
high wire wire all the time.
And, um, you know, and,
and we, we, you know,
push everything out to
other podcast apps as well.
So if, you know, somebody wants to
listen in a true fans or, you know,
the automatic or, or
fountain or whatever, all that works too.
So yeah, we basically, yeah, we basically
give the station an RSS feed, uh,
for the station
that includes the most recent episode
of every podcast they have in there.
Plus their live feed.
And it's really cool when you, when
you show it to people like, Oh, look,
here it is in the podcast
guru, podcast, attic fountain.
And what true fans, what, what,
what, how does that work?
What?
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
You can do that.
These stations have their own apps too.
And it works in there.
It's just, so yeah, it's just, it's
just part of that whole philosophy of,
of podcasting is of be everywhere.
You know, the content
needs to be everywhere.
So I don't, I'm not sure, I don't know
where you're, where you're headed,
but this fits in really well with
what I was, uh, I, I'd kind of,
I had sort of a thing that I wanted
to talk about today,
but then at the last minute I heard
power this morning and I kind
of really changed to,
I felt like I wanted to talk about
NPR and kind of public broadcasting.
Well, you do, you do you boo.
You do you boo.
I mean, it's part of like, so
much has happened since, uh,
while I was in the forest.
Funny thing happened while
I was in the forest.
I came back and Stephen
Colbert had been canceled.
NPR lost its funding
and it was like, yeah.
And podcasting just got
a little bit better.
Yeah, I mean, this kind of all fit
that we're talking about the radius,
you know, radio centric
and nature of everything in radios,
radio stations making the digital
transition, which feel like
they, they just didn't
ever fully grasp how to
do in a way that didn't hurt them, their
traditional like revenue model.
Um, I mean, I, I feel, you know, I'm
not, I'm not the expert on that topic,
but the conversation
we have with Rocky was very
interesting around, you know,
what their trepidation with, with
digital and with internet, uh,
streaming based on how they got
screwed by Mark Cuban and other
people in the early days who
just kind of like used them to,
to make a fortune themselves
and discarded them, you
know, to a dustbin.
Yes.
Um, I mean, like the, the first,
the first few minutes of this
week's pod news weekly review,
like I said, I had a whole, I had a whole
set of topics I want to talk about,
but like after hearing those first
few minutes, I was like, no,
it just gave me so many
thoughts about this topic.
Okay.
Um, and I mean, so I
guess NPR, NPR is such a,
is so important to podcasting because they
were so early and they were one
of the first ones to pop up.
I mean, back even, I think it was
even before we called it podcasting,
they were already sniffing around.
They were there very early.
What's your, what's your, um, uh,
buddy over there at WGBH
that Tony Khan, Tony Khan.
Yeah.
Um, and so I mean, there's this
whole, there's, it's like,
there's multiple things that the
death of traditional mainstream,
whatever you want to call it,
mainstream media, whether
it's, you know, TV or cable or, uh, radio.
I mean, that's been predicted forever,
but so as so often is the
case with predictions like
this, it actually, it may
ultimately come to pass,
but it takes a lot longer
than you think it will.
Yeah.
This is why I'm not a billionaire because
I always come up with great ideas.
At least 10 years too early.
Too early.
Yeah.
And then someone else goes
off and makes money on it.
Like, how, how did Joe Rogan get two,
two, $300 million and I got nothing?
You're not getting your
royalty check from podcasting?
No.
Um, so, I mean, that, that's, so radio and
TV and, and they're just sort of slow.
They're dying so slowly.
Yeah.
It was a very slow burn.
And so PBS, I don't know this, this, this,
this thing about NPR getting their funding
cut, they mentioned it a little bit.
They were mostly focused on the BBC
and, uh, Spain, uh, public media,
but you know, NPR,
uh, is, was really corporation for
public broadcasting lost, um, you know,
lost its federal funding,
which flows to PBS and NPR through the
corporation for public broadcasting.
And I just wanted to kind of like
visit this, this topic for a second,
because there's, I hear
constant misunderstanding about
the way the money flow works.
And there, everybody
has a different version
of what ultimately is not how this works.
Um, so PBS said that, that, that,
that money that they lost, um,
made up about 20% of their revenue.
That's, that's a big deal for PBS, but
you know, underwriters and donations,
I guess they make up 80%.
So there's 20%, they can,
they can survive that.
I mean, underwriters are
advertisers and if they
do some content and programming changes
to try to attract new audiences and that
kind of thing, they can survive a 20% cut.
Just to, to set one thing kind
of straight in the beginning,
PBS purchases a lot of that
programming from commercial
production companies as does NPR.
Yes.
So it's not like them, you know, so, um,
often spot and a lot of it, PBS is a lot
of military industrial complex, you know,
like Boeing and Archer
Daniel Midland company
and, you know, yeah, it's not
really like consumer oriented.
They know exactly what their
audience is and their, if anything,
it's virtue signaling, but
still, um, and, and with NPR,
it's even more prevalent how
the money flows because the,
the local stations actually have to buy
the national programming, uh, through NPR.
And, you know, so it's very convoluted.
Yeah.
And that's the, that's the real flow
is PBS can survive the 20% cut.
NPR is going to be more affected.
Uh, they're, they're going to get the
bigger hit from this because most,
like you said, most, the money
flow is that most of the,
of that money from the
government goes to the
member stations, which then turn around and
buy the content from the NPR mothership.
And so the, the, the money does
end up at the NPR mothership.
It just goes through a
securitist route to get there.
So less money to the member stations
means less money to purchase the content,
which ultimately means less
money to NPR mothership.
So that's, that's how they get hurt
out of this pro out of, out of this.
There is one other thing.
NPR pays an exorbitant amount of money.
I forget how much, but
it's millions a year to
deliver the programming to the
NPR stations via satellite.
That is such a waste of money.
Yeah.
Yes.
There must, and the,
knowing the way government operates and
not just government, but government
and nonprofits and NGOs and knowing the
way that whole thing is put together,
this is, there's probably a
couple of people who have
contracts to deliver that through
this old satellite system.
And they're just, they've been getting
paid all this money for all these years.
And you know, you don't want
to upset the apple cart.
No, no.
A lot of people, yeah, it's gravy train.
Yeah.
It's the grandson, the, the, the owner
of whatever this delivery network is,
the grandson of some
Senator or something like,
you know, you never,
you never know how this
stuff works, but, um,
but it got me thinking, you know, so
the point of public broadcasting,
like what, what is the actual point?
So that meaning tax funded broadcasting,
and at least in the U S this is governed by
the public broadcasting act of 1967, um,
which established the corporation
for public broadcasting
NPR was created a few
years later, but, uh,
by the corporation for
public broadcasting and
reading from that act, the
goals of, of doing that,
of establishing this nonprofit corporation
for public broadcasting that
would receive tax dollars.
The goals were things like this quote,
it is in the public interest
to encourage the growth
and development of public
radio and television,
including the use of such
media for instructional
education and cultural purposes.
Uh, another quote is, uh, another
quote is this is from the act itself.
It says to constitute an expression of
diversity and excellence, you know,
so the public, public
broadcasting gets a hit from, you know,
super right wing people, uh, for being,
you know, uh, lefty and
that kind of thing.
And, but a lot of what
they're programming is,
is actually in keeping with their mandate.
Uh, another, another quote
is it is in the public
interest to encourage the development of
programming that involves
creative risks and that
addresses the needs of
unserved and underserved
audiences, particularly
children and minorities.
So that's in the, the
bill that created them.
So, you know, a lot, a lot of
their programming is doing that.
Yeah.
So they, they are being
true to their mission
statement as given to them by Congress.
Um, the pro, you know,
that's not really a problem.
The problem has come in with the, the
prohibitions that were also in that act.
And so for instance, this
one, it says, quote,
the corporation may not
contribute to or otherwise
support any political party or candidate
for elective public office, unquote.
Right.
Now you can, you can support
someone without supporting someone.
Yes.
Yes, absolutely.
And you see that done and
you see that done every
week from pulpits and churches, you know,
people make statements
that don't, you know,
because churches are also
because they're tax exempt.
Do you know that the IRS just
released a statement about the,
it's called the Johnson Amendment.
Uh, President Johnson added an
amendment to the IRS law and that was,
I don't know, that must've
been early sixties.
Um, no 501c3 nonprofit can,
that's why you have 501c4s because
that's a lobbying nonprofit,
which is not tax deductible.
But the 501c3s, which most
churches are, they can't, um,
they cannot favor any
political candidates.
And the IRS just issued
an opinion and they said,
this will no longer hold true for houses
of worship because it is the same as
talking about politics inside your family.
Now how that works with, with podcasts
by pastors and stuff like that.
I don't know.
Right.
You know, and, or when they
stream a service live,
I think that's kind of questionable,
but that was just like two weeks ago.
That was an opinion the IRS released.
Oh, interesting.
Okay.
Yeah.
That, that's when, you know,
the way, well, the way, yeah,
the way churches have gotten
around that forever, that, that ambiguity
there is bus, you know, they'll,
you know, you make statements from, you
know, from your sermon or whatever,
and you don't mention a particular
candidate or that kind of
thing, but you, you said,
you mentioned all the things around it.
I'm voting red.
If you know what I mean, wink,
wink, wink, wink, nudge, nudge.
Yes.
Right.
I'm just saying, make America great again.
Yeah.
It's like, or, you know, like,
uh, if it's a, you know,
more of a left leaning church,
you miss like, uh, we're with her.
Yeah.
You know, quote, you know, like, by the
way, during the 20, uh, 2024 election,
black churches, man, they, they
were just all out vote for Kamala.
They were just saying it flat out.
It was, it was pretty crazy.
Like, okay.
But so, you know, in, in PR we've,
you know, we've played clips of, uh,
of on the media, uh, you know,
which is a, uh, NPR show.
We've played clips of them where
they just flat out say Trump,
you know, Trump's a fascist.
We keep telling people this,
but they won't listen to us.
That's right.
Literally.
That's what they said.
They won't listen.
Well, we're no good.
Yeah.
So this is the, the problem is not
with the problem is not with their,
their following their mandate,
which they mostly do.
Problem is that they've, they've gone
so far, um, against the prohibitions.
And they're just basically that it's,
there's another one in here that says,
quote, strict adherence to objectivity
and balance in all programs
or series of programs of a controversial
nature, unquote, you know, and
it's just not the case anymore.
And I don't actually,
I don't have a problem with the
leftness or rightness of any particular
broadcaster, including NPR and PBS.
It's, um, I'm sort of immune to it.
I, it doesn't, I don't listen
to those things anyway.
Mostly I used to, I used to listen
to a lot of NPR when I was younger.
I, it's, I find it kind of boring these
days, so I don't listen to it anymore,
but, um, I don't really have a problem
with the left, right of all this.
Um, cause I think the
leftward trend of NPR and
PBS is really just more of a
general trend that follow it.
So it follows the, the
education and income brackets,
the more money and the more education
a person has, the more
likely they are to be left
on the left side of the
political spectrum.
And so, you know, and why that is, is a
question that people like Thomas Frank,
um, you can read his books have,
they've contributed to answering.
It's a hard, it's a hard question.
It's multifactorial, you know,
factorial, but it, it really,
that trend started under the
Bill Clinton years and it's kind of,
and it's just increased
exponentially since then.
But much of NPR and member
stations are tied to
Washington DC and those are the wealthiest
zip codes in the country and universities.
Like our local NPR station is UAB
university here in Birmingham,
the United university of
Alabama, Birmingham.
It's, it's housed on their campus.
So there's your answer to you.
It's an organic thing.
They trend, the NPR and
PBS trended left because
their staff and their
listeners trended more
towards educated and high income.
So this is what I, it's not a new
term, but it's audience capture.
And, and I've dealt with
this for over 17 years,
whenever Dvorak and I
disagreed with general
opinion, my timeline fills
up with, I'm unsubscribing.
I'm no longer donating.
This is no good.
And we, we're just like, oh, fine.
You know, if we don't get enough
donations, we'll go do something else.
That's always been our, uh, our take.
So we had alternative
opinions during COVID.
We had alternative opinions about Ukraine.
We have definitely had alternative
opinions about, uh, who runs,
who America is real or
Israel America and the amount of hate
and anger and threats that I can.
And, and I, I see why it's so easy for many
podcasters in particular to go, oh crap.
Uh, well, my audience doesn't like that.
So I, I must be wrong or, you know, and
I think that's the same with all media.
You're in a milieu and that's what
you're, that's what you're identifying.
You're, you're in the,
you're literally on campus.
So you're going to be in a milieu.
Um, but it's very, very tough to
stand up and say, no, I'm just,
I just have a different opinion.
And this is my opinion.
If you don't like it, then don't
listen or don't donate or whatever.
That's fine.
You're not hurting me.
Uh, you think you are, but you're not,
which is why I have a donation
model and not advertising
because advertisers would
have gone away immediately.
Yeah.
I mean, the, the, the NPR mothership
is in Washington DC and it's very,
they're, Washington DC is
a, is a place, a place of extreme wealth.
And so you're going to get a
trend towards a trend left.
And in the universe, the
universities, which many NPR station,
your member stations, you
know, are on, on university
campuses are started that way.
The university professors
and university staff are
also very well paid and
that's a very, and,
and highly educated.
So that's also another
trend towards the left.
It's just not, it's an,
it happened organically.
It's an organic process.
There's, it's, you, you could have
almost predicted it based on, you know,
just seeing where history was going.
So it's not, it's not surprising.
And it's, it's honestly not even that
big of a deal, except here's my,
here's where I kind
of hit, you know, here's where it hits
me or here's, here's where my mind went.
I don't, I don't think
the problem is with,
is with a certain political
bias problem I see
is that, um, being publicly
funded with tax dollars
did not keep that political
skew from happening.
So what's the point, you know,
because the idea here is that, okay,
we're going to, we're
going to publicly fund this media
with tax dollars and we're,
and that's going to allow, I'm speaking
as the government here,
that's going to allow us to dictate
to this organization that they're
not allowed to show political
bias, but that did not work.
And so if the, if the, if the receiving
of tax dollars through congressional,
uh, dictate, dictate, if that does
not keep the bias from happening,
then they're really no different
from any other non-tax
funded organization.
And at that point, why
give them tax money?
Because there's only,
there's only one argument for giving
them tax money is there, is that you
can establish guardrails,
fairness and balance.
And if that does not, if that
doesn't effectuate in reality,
then there's no reason to have
a tax funded organization like that.
So, you know, what I'm saying
is you can have two entities,
Fox news and NPR that both skew
hard to the left or the right.
One gets tax money and the other doesn't.
So the presence or lack of tax money
as a balancing agent doesn't work.
I have, I have only one
real problem with NPR
and this hit me four years ago and it hit
me just three weeks ago.
We had a devastating flood here in the
hill country, 20 minutes South of me.
The only reason we weren't affected is
because we're on at a higher elevation,
uh, comfort,
Curville, Hunt, Centerpoint.
I mean, everyone has seen the images,
by the way, it's like the Grand Canyon,
unless you've actually been there.
You don't understand how vast that is.
And for all this noise, radio has for my,
I've been a radio guy
since I was 13 years old
and built my first radio transmitter.
Radio is inherently a local medium.
When this hit and you turned on KTXI 90.1,
Hill Country's NPR station during
this tragedy, what did you hear?
This is fresh air with Terry Gross.
That made me so mad or, Hey
everybody, it's time for Marketplace.
And that was, I was
like, what in the world?
And you know, so I, I was running spots
on Hello Fred, you know, all kinds.
It was useless.
Uh, the rock station, um, uh, uh,
was it, uh, KRV, I think, uh,
my buddy Cody over there,
he was, he'd stopped this
whole morning show and
wasn't playing music and was just trying
to coordinate stuff on the air.
You know, and that's a very small, very
niche rock station in Curville, but NPR,
our national treasure.
No, there was no one there.
They didn't know what to do.
They hadn't, they had no procedure
for all this noise about, Oh,
what are you doing emergency?
No, none of that.
None of that.
And that was the same four years
ago with Snowmageddon in Austin.
In fact, it was fresh air.
That was the same show that
was running when electricity
was out for days and we sat in our
cars trying to get some information.
I want some fresh water.
And it was, uh, you know,
literally, um, the top 40 station,
the weather guy was doing,
uh, all kinds of updates and reports.
And, and I guess that kind of flows into
what is, what is the point anymore?
What is the point of radio, which
is going back to the beginning,
which is why we're, we've
built something that we believe
transitions radio to the digital realm,
which is no longer bound
by terrestrial lines.
You know, Starlink, um, a,
one of the no agenda guys,
he organized the meetup
last Saturday here in town.
I'm like, what are you doing?
Oh, I'm here for, uh, for flood relief.
I said, what are you doing?
So I talked to the guy,
he has a nonprofit.
It's called disaster lab
tech, disaster lab tech.org.
And he says, and so he's funded by donors
and, uh, tech companies give him gear.
He goes in, so he literally
flew in from, from Holland,
from the South of Holland, flew
in, brought in, he has flight
cases, the whole deal.
He sets up a wifi mesh network with
a Starlink, multiple Starlink, uh,
satellite dishes, and
just sets up communications for everybody.
QR code, boom, you're
online, you're connected.
Everybody can talk.
They've got IP based radios
and they leave it there.
They don't take it back.
They leave it.
They leave all the tech there.
That's what I'm talking about.
That's useful.
That's cool.
Yeah.
I mean, they, so I guess
I'm actually heading
somewhere with this and
that is that I think
NPR, I think I got to sort of to, um, wrap
kind of ways that I'm want to, that, that
this is heading from my, in my mind, NPR,
I think they made a terrible mistake.
Um, when they canceled, they
gutted the wrong people.
They got rid of their podcasting
group or didn't get rid of them.
But they, they just gutted that
whole, pretty much, pretty much, man.
They killed the future.
They did.
Yeah.
They, they killed the future to, to
preserve a declining, a declining business.
And they should have
done the exact opposite.
Yep.
They should have, they
should have doubled down.
They should have doubled down.
Yep.
And, and converted into a
podcast first organization
who also took some of
that content and stuck
it on broadcast radio for the member
stations that, that, that they had.
I, so I think that on a, I'm actually
hopeful about this whole thing.
I think it's, this is what it is.
You know, do you have, you know,
those people that say, um,
like they own a successful business
and they say, you know, I should
have, I should have quit my job.
I got fired.
And then I started this business
and now it's successful.
And I should have done this 10 years ago.
It felt horrible at the time to get fired.
I thought I was really scared.
I thought everything
was going to be awful.
But in retrospect, it was the best
thing that ever happened to me.
Yeah.
I think that could be the same thing here.
I think this could be a
really good thing for
these member stations to disconnect them
from their, their extreme dependence
on the, on the mothership,
let them do their thing
and, but, and build up
their local donation base
and their local programming even more than
it already is and connect.
And then the mothership should
double down on podcast content,
do some sort of rev share
with, with the member stations.
They need to re they,
what I'm saying is they need to blow
up this whole model and, and rethink
this thing from the ground up
with a digital first strategy.
And when it comes to digital first
strategy, this was the problem.
They had shows with 50
people working on the show.
You know, it didn't make any money.
Yeah, that didn't make any money.
And the, and you know, the,
the blueprint is there.
Use your audience, involve your audience,
make your audience, your producers.
The blueprint is there.
They come, they approach
it from an elite position.
Like, well, you know, we know how to
do this and, you know, it's like, no,
it doesn't work that way.
If Dvorak and I, if we had, even if
we had an editor, like, oh, well,
you should edit the show
because we can't do that.
We wouldn't be able to make it.
It's like, no, we, we
can't hire another person.
So we've got to do it ourselves.
And what we did is we outsourced it to
the audience and said, congratulations.
You're now all producers.
You contribute time, talent, or treasure.
Lots of people have no time or talent.
They want to contribute.
Like, I'll write a check.
Turns out a lot of people like doing that.
But man, the boots on the ground from
every vocation, every type of person,
every situation,
it's, it has been the success of the show.
And that's what NPR should look at.
They're stuck, you know, and by the
way, Terry Gross making, you know,
$300,000 just for that one
show, public information.
This, this financial
shakeup may unstick them.
You know, and that's the, that's what I'm
looking, you know, that's what I'm hopeful
for, but because NPR, NPR gets a bad
rap for being stuck in the past.
And in a lot of ways, I think,
I think they're not so much
stuck in the past as they are,
they're shackled to, to
their funding model.
Yeah.
They can't, they, they could not
figure out a way to get out of it.
And now they can, they have freedom
now that they didn't have before.
Good luck.
I mean, they've obviously got very,
they have talented people there.
They have many talented people there.
They have forward looking people there.
I mean, uh, that, you know, that we've
talked to about podcasting stuff, uh,
in the past privately, they've got, they
have a lot of people there that are in,
and they were the earliest adopted, one
of the earliest adopters of podcasting.
They are actually very
forward looking and talented.
They just, when somebody gets tied
to Washington, the way they were,
it really corrupts the process.
It slows you down to where you are stuck.
They're stuck in 1967.
Sorry.
No, PBS is the one that I
really want to talk about.
I think I've changed my mind
on HLS video and podcasting.
I mean, I was, you know, I
wanted this thing to work.
Uh, but actually I think
now that I think about it,
I think it's actually imperative that we
try to get this thing to work in
podcast apps and on the hosting side.
Explain.
Um, so, um, I think it
was some stuff Stan,
Sam was saying on power
that made me, that just,
this just kind of hit me
is we, things like, uh,
video based public broadcasting that needs
a place to land and it's going until
traditional linear television is going to die.
I mean, whether it's 20 years from now,
five years from now, I don't know,
but it is heading off a cliff.
And I think there's only
two places that it lands.
YouTube or podcast.
Yeah.
Amen to that.
I complete, this is, this is very deep.
I hadn't actually thought
about it that way.
It would require them to see the light.
Obviously.
Um, it would, man, it would
really boost the whole,
the whole ecosystem to an enormous degree.
In fact, I would say I'd
like to now get a Senator
or representative to start introducing
bills to refund public media,
decentralized, sorry, Sam,
let's not do freemium because
that's where it's going.
That's where the NPR and PBS
and other public broadcasters,
as we clearly see with BBC and,
and other public broadcasters
around the world,
they're moving towards
subscription freemium.
It's the, it's the wrong
direction in my humble opinion.
People, if you want to spend tax
dollars, build out the infrastructure,
spend it in a commercial
manner so that PBS, as an example,
can actually subsidize the
infrastructure, decentralized
infrastructure, not,
not, don't centralize,
don't try to be the
boss of everything, you
know, but all of this, well,
we're going to block that app
because they're making money
off of us because they make
$3.99 a month from us,
from someone who buys a
premium version of the app.
Who we, who we, who we, I say, this, this,
this would be a very good
use of taxpayer money
and it would benefit not just America,
it would benefit the world really,
but they're all so
stuck in, got to make money, got to
monetize, got to get ads, got to do this,
got to do that, blah, blah, blah, blah.
You know, the content
is almost secondary at
this point to many of
these people and it's
because of their own salaries.
I get it.
300 grand is great.
Oh yeah.
I don't want to rock that boat.
Yeah.
I mean, the NPR, don't, don't
the like morning edition people,
don't they make like half a
million a year or something?
Yeah.
400,000 each.
I mean, that's, that's a lot of,
you don't want to upset that
apple cart if you're the
one getting that paycheck,
but, but everybody downstream,
the staff downstream from that,
they're not getting paid
that, those kinds of bucks.
So they, they are, they will be have,
they will be willing to
make these transitions.
And, you know, just, and
you, you look at, and that,
this kind of what I was bringing
up Stephen Colbert, you
know, the quote unquote,
the talent that gets paid the big bucks.
They, they're not sacred.
They can go away as well.
When the, when the, when
the format is unprofitable
and it no longer makes
sense to have the content
there and to pay for it
when you're losing money,
the people at the top that make a lot
of money have to adjust down or go
figure out something else to do.
And that leaves an entire staff
there with the ability to pivot.
And I think we can just, you know, this,
I think we just have to
make sure this stuff
doesn't land on YouTube.
I mean, it may ultimately land some
of it there, but I just feel like if,
if WNYC, they should be able to
contract with Buzzsprout for
their video delivery
or WGBH should be able
to like, what if the, you know, the, okay,
they, maybe they choose rss.com, uh,
TPT in Minnesota, uh,
public broadcasting, they,
maybe they go with
blueberry or transistor.
I just think we should
be ready for a situation
where we have public
media and actually, and,
and other entities too, but a lot of them
are going to want to do it themselves,
but public media to contract
out with, with podcasts,
delivery companies to deliver their video.
I mean, cause they, they've
already public media,
they know podcasting they've
built, they've built continent.
Well, see, and I love you
for being an idealist.
I'm the more pirate guy.
I'm like, screw it.
We're going to do it ourselves.
And, and my vision for
local radio is churches.
They already got that antenna on it,
that dipole and a vertical antenna.
They got, they got a dipole on the roof.
Um, and I'm like, you know, this is how
you speak into your local community.
And by the way, value for
value based business.
I spoke, uh, this past
Wednesday, I spoke, uh,
I think it was like 45 early 20 year olds
at the Patriot Academy, uh,
here in Fredericksburg.
The pay, do you know, do you
know about the Patriot Academy?
No, I never heard of it.
Well, from the outside, it looks like, uh,
that's where you go to
turn your kid into a
Christian nationalist militia.
Okay.
Do they have flyers that
they drop from helicopters?
But in reality, they've, they've, on the
inside, they've got a 90 acre campus.
It's all nonprofit.
So it's all funded by community.
They've been around for 20 years.
They've been doing this,
but now they finally have a campus
for the first time in their history
and it's in Fredericksburg.
And, um, so kids who are on a gap
year or right out of college,
you go in and it's, uh,
they have tiny homes.
Everybody stays on campus.
Um, and they've rebuilt the houses
of Congress and the Senate.
And so they teach these young
people how to write a bill,
how to get it into committee,
how to get it out of committee,
how to, how to argue it.
And they have, you know, all
kinds of speakers coming in.
And, uh, so Rick Green, who, who runs
it, he said, would you come and speak?
I said, okay.
And I wasn't quite sure.
Like, all right, I'll just tell my history
of media, uh, to these 20 year olds.
And I realized pretty
quickly that every 95% of
all of my cultural pop references
went way over their head.
Like they don't know who
Chevy Chase is anymore.
Elvis Presley don't know
who Elvis Presley is, but,
but when I got to the media part for
them and you know, I was
able to entertain them.
I've, I've got enough stories, you
know, they do remember some people.
You just told them about the poop app.
I just said, I'm, I was on Joe Rogan.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, we know.
And now we know who you are.
Um, when I got to the media part
and I explained algos and they all,
they all know algos, they get it.
They understand it, how you have
to feed it to make it work.
And then I started talking about art.
None of them had heard of RSS, no idea.
And so I went through kind of a
top line summary, explained it.
And I said, you know,
ultimately this is going to cost you
about 15 to $20 a month, but that
will save you in everything you do from
that moment on because you control it.
It is your, your signal, your transmitter.
And, uh, you know, and, and
went through the, you know,
the most powerful sentence in broadcasting
is wherever you get your podcast.
How does that work?
Why is this important?
And of all the stories I told, and
I had a lot of stories, man, they,
they lined up at the end
of this to talk about RSS.
Really?
Oh yeah.
But they're like, this, this
seems really important.
Mr. Curry.
It's so weird when people say,
Mr. Curry, Mr. Curry, Mr. Curry.
That's my dad.
I know.
I was like, ah, okay.
Flinch.
Um, and value for value.
They love that.
Like, really?
You can do that?
And I told my story, you know, my, my
no agenda story, how we, how we started
implementing that and came up
with the phrase and, you know,
I was so positive about that
because they all have an Instagram,
a TikTok, a YouTube channel and,
and all the things I
was saying like, yeah, no, I know.
It was like, if I don't upload something,
then, you know, I go down and,
you know, it's all about the likes
and the clicks and then the light
bulb really goes on when you say, you
know, you can just do a podcast
about your, your school team, about,
you know, things happening
in your town and people in your town
will support you if you ask them.
And so I was very encouraged by that.
And so for me, that's, I, I have
no patience for these people.
Uh, you know, the PBS's, NPR's and
I just have no patience for them.
I want the excited 20 year old who
just wants to get going, do something,
this excited about it.
And they, and quite frankly,
enough of the boomers, me, uh,
I've given into it now, 1964.
Okay.
I was the face of generation
X would call me a boomer.
We don't really have the, where's
the next generation of podcasters?
Where are they?
Where's the 20 year olds?
Okay.
We have the millennial media
offensive, but they're millennials.
Where is this next generation?
That's who we need to be speaking to.
That's who we need to get into this.
Otherwise it, everything's doomed.
Yeah.
I'm this, the, the age issue came,
you know, it just comes up a lot.
Well, you know, traditional
television is, um, you know,
like let's just say television,
traditional television
is like a bunch of old
people that watch actually not the case.
I mean, so my, I mean.
Well, the numbers say, the
numbers say that's true, Dave.
The numbers say that's true.
No, I didn't mean it.
I misspoke.
What I'm saying is it is the case
that tradition, that linear media is,
is watched by, by older people.
Content is not only older people.
Correct.
So like the, the most
popular content on all
the streaming media platforms are the old,
are like Seinfeld and The Office.
Mm-hmm.
And these shows that are
like 10, 15, 20 years old.
30, 30 years old.
30 years old.
And so the, it's the, the content that,
and that's the problem
with a lot of what public
media became is it's boring.
It's always the content,
always the content.
It has to stop being boring.
Think back.
Like, you know, I think
back to public media,
the content that I really
liked and in the past
and stuck with me, things like Ken
Burns documentaries, Car Talk, Cosmos.
I mean, like these were good programs,
but there's no, all that stuff's gone.
They don't have that stuff anymore.
And it's just boring.
You turn on, you know,
you turn on an NPR member station
on Sunday morning and it's like,
it's that, that game show of
the wait, wait, don't tell me.
Wait, wait, wait, don't tell me.
Yeah.
Nobody, it's boring.
Nobody cares about that.
Nobody's going to listen to that.
They've, they've got to get
the content back to be king.
And if you do that and focus
and start pushing it out over,
over podcasts where you can get
it everywhere and just forget
the whole, let the member,
the member stations can
take care of themselves.
They need to go and
address that whole market.
And they just, they're going
through the same growing
pain as a growing pains
that Christian radio is.
They're trying to find out
how to survive and reinvent
themselves into a digital first medium.
And they're going to have
to do that on their own.
They can, NPR cannot do that for them.
It's just, they can't.
And so that, yeah, I, I think this whole,
I think this whole thing, it, yes,
the age thing is an issue, but
it's only an issue on the medium.
If they trend, if, if these public
media people transition to, to,
we're going to be podcast
first, we're going to be digital first.
And then, you know, what, and then
the member stations can, you know,
redesign their profile based on that.
They, I think they can survive and
I think there'll be better for it.
But I just, do you hear this?
Do you hear that?
Yeah.
That's you speaking into the wind.
I know.
But I don't think they'll
have a choice though.
You know, I mean, NPR is, it's PBS, PBS
is going to survive longer, but NPR,
this was a death blow.
They're, this is a hard one.
They're, they are going to have to
reorganize to survive, you know, and,
and a lot, that's like
getting fired from your job.
Yes.
You got to figure out what comes next.
What do you do next?
Exactly right.
Yeah.
Um, anyway, that's, that was,
I just think it was an important
topic because NPR actually
is very important to podcasting and,
you know, they're, they, they, they're
they, for a long time, they were,
they were 50% of what
podcasting was, was NPR shows.
Again, they were the first ones on the
homepage of Apple and iTunes when it started.
Yeah.
And, and I don't want to,
and I want to see them make this
transition successfully because
I think in the process,
having to face reality financially
means they will naturally rebalance
the other things that,
that are causing them trouble like
bias and all these other issues.
I think when you have to live in the real
world, you have, you, you don't, you know,
you don't get to, you don't get
to ignore your audience anymore.
Well, so I'm in agreement with you
that HLS video would be great and,
and I will support, I
will support the idea.
I just, I wish we could put a lot more
focus into lit and funding and location,
uh, because that, I think
we can do it all at once.
Well, dev cycles.
Something has to be one or the other.
Dev cycles at, uh, at hosting companies
are, are a scarcity, you know?
Well, the good thing is most
of the hosting companies
already have a fund and they already
support the funding tag.
That's true.
You know, so, you know, between lit and
lit and, um, HLS can go hand in hand.
I was, um, yeah, you know this, but
I was asked to do a keynote at, uh,
NRB in February,
the National Religious
Broadcasters Conference.
Yep.
And I'm going to go completely lit.
I'm going to go lit
funding the whole thing.
I'm just going to lay it all out
there and tell them they're dying.
Adam's talk was lit.
And again, say, you're dead.
You're dead to me.
Just think about it.
Think about, ah, forget about it.
I mean, it's get rid of the transmitters.
You can pay your host
the 300 grand a year.
Get rid of the transmitters.
Get, wake up.
Is that how much a cost per
year for a transmitter?
300 grand?
You know, that's a good question.
Well, first of all, AM or
FM makes a big difference.
Um, so let's say, what is the cost to run
a 100,000 watt FM station transmitter?
I mean, who knows if I'll get an
answer here, but you never know.
Could come out of, okay.
About, um, well, of course you have to
have your tower, your infrastructure,
your licensing,
all of that, but, uh, it seems like
20 grand a month in power alone.
Seems about right.
Yeah.
And that, you know, that doesn't
include maintenance and all this stuff.
And there's a lot, a lot that
goes into, and that's FM.
AM, man.
You're, you're, you're burning diesel.
Let me see.
What is, uh, AM station?
Is digital, uh, radio, is that any
cheaper or is it roughly the same?
Digital?
What do you mean digital radio?
But you like, uh.
Like DAB and stuff.
DAB.
Well, but DAB has no reach in America.
Yeah, I know.
But I mean, if, if like, uh, what was
the, um, was it HD radio and all that?
Yeah.
Is that the same?
Well, you just run it, you just run it
on a sideband of your existing signal.
Okay.
I guess.
So I, I mean, obviously there's equipment
costs, but that, that was, that failed.
And it's just so obvious.
Look, look at the room,
look at the room there is.
I mean, people are only listening.
What was the stat?
It's pretty low.
Like below 30% are listening to
audio in the car that is not radio.
You know, there's, there's your,
there's your room to grow.
70 more percent to go.
You know, just give people
some, give people a reason.
You know, it's all about the content.
No agenda is not on Spotify.
Hasn't heard us.
You know, people just use a different app.
No, those guys.
I want to hear them,
but I'll have to use a different
app because Spotify doesn't do it.
You know?
Yeah.
It's, it's gotta be, it's
gotta be a podcast first.
It's just a podcast first, first future.
I said, I said, I'm back.
I said, cause he was talking about AI right
up my alley, but I spanked him on that.
Get over my knee, Glenn Beck.
I'm going to spank your bottom boy.
His eyes got all wide.
I'm like, no, no, no.
Um, I said, really leave
the smartphone out of it.
But the two most important, um,
technologies of the past 20
years is RSS and Bitcoin.
And they're, they're both owned by no one.
They're universally deployed.
They work.
They're unstoppable.
And they're inherently not sexy.
You know?
So.
Yeah.
It's old, old, boring technology.
Old, boring technology for
very non-boring content.
Yep.
That's exactly right.
We got, we got some, uh,
we got a couple of notes.
We got some feedback.
Oh, feedback.
Yeah.
Uh, Dreb.
Was there money attached to it?
Like a boostogram or was just feedback?
Just feedback.
Oh, okay.
Uh, Dreb said, uh, that OP3,
that the OP3.dev IP address is getting
blocked by some corporate firewalls.
Yeah.
Palo Alto, I think.
That's no good.
No.
Well, typically these are
things that come, you know,
someone will load in a new blacklist.
We've had this, I've had this happen so
many times and most of these blacklists,
you can go in and you can say, Hey,
you know, we're not a spam outfit.
Here's what we're doing.
And they'll, and it will
remove you some auto remove.
If you just go up, show up and
say, Hey, this is not true.
Um, this is an ongoing problem.
No agenda gets blocked on all kinds of
corporate firewalls for, um, um, what is it?
Um, what is it?
The term they use extremist views.
Oh, Oh, Nathan just posted on the, on the
Mastodon that, uh, Radiotopia, that's PRX.
They've implemented, uh, his
fall is podcast follow tag.
Ooh, very cool.
That's not even a formalized tag yet.
Now, what was, what was the company that
was, that had just switched to funding?
That's, that's a public media.
I mean, that's what I'm saying.
They're, they're, they're, they're,
that's the public media exchange.
Yeah, but they're, but, but
it's, they're the same.
They're, they're in the same circles.
I mean, they're hungry.
Yeah.
I think there's people there
at these organizations
that are hungry to do these things.
Yes.
Well, when the hosts get hungry,
then things will change.
Well, they're not going to be hungry
because they make a lot of money.
They're not, they're by
definition, not hungry.
Hunger is the mother of all
invention or is it something else?
Hunger requires not, not lots of money.
Definitely, definitely helps.
Definitely helps.
This, this is really cool.
I guess we've got to formalize the tag
now that somebody's actually using this.
Go for it.
Now, do you want to talk about
any of these, um, um, what is it?
The, uh, or the L402 or there was another,
there was a whole conversation about,
uh, podcast OAuth endpoints.
Have you seen that GitHub entry?
Created a repo for the, for the secure
RSSL4 tooth stuff this morning.
Daniel Matthews put this in.
He's from, where is this?
Is there a link for this?
Uh, I can give it to you
real quick right now.
It's a discussion.
Yeah, you're right, Nathan.
Andrew over at PRX, you're right.
They're, they are on the ball.
They got, they got stuff coming too.
They're, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm excited, I'm
excited about what they can get done.
You got it.
Optimistically skeptical.
It's okay.
Yeah.
Uh, let's see.
Exclusive episodes on the RSS feed.
And the reason I ask is because this was
a, you're not on that, uh, WhatsApp group.
There's a whole conversation about it,
but even about L402, you know, not,
not everybody's on board with that.
Um, oh, wait, there's, is
this, uh, L402 failed for me.
I was trying to subscribe.
Uh, I became a subscriber of this week
in Bitcoin mainly because, you know,
it's a, it's the fountain
fountain hosting round Robin.
And I, I like, uh, Chris and
I like his, his podcast.
And so I said, I'm just testing something.
I'm doing a, he did a freemium
episode of one minute and 20 seconds.
And I said, if not, if you subscribe,
then you can get this bonus content.
I'm like, okay, I'll go
for your bonus content.
But then it failed and I
got some kind of error.
I'm not sure what's going on.
How did it fail?
Uh, I posted a, I posted a picture on,
uh, on the Mastodon, uh, the error,
which showed up, the error
was, um, state failed source.
Well, yeah, you should get a
402 if you don't have a token,
but you should have a token already.
I'm tokenless.
Yeah.
Dan, Daniel Matthews, Nathan says,
uh, Daniel Matthews founded Podacy.
Okay.
I'll, I'll respond.
Thanks for linking this.
I'll respond to this.
Cause I think, I mean, he clearly has put
a lot of work into this proposal here.
I think L4O2 is farther along.
It looks like, uh, it looks like, um,
Russell mentioned to him
that he's going to send him,
uh, the L4O2 secure RSS documents.
I think, I mean, I think we've already got
implementations in multiple places of,
of L4O2 support.
So I'm, I'm really reluctant to try
to build some new spec on this.
So I think, uh, I think
we should try to pull him
into what's already happening
rather than build a new spec.
Maybe hopefully our,
hopefully Russell, Oscar and,
or Oscar can get the documentation for
the current L4O2 up on the, the namespace.
And we can just link him over there.
I think, I mean, uh, yeah,
it's a good, it's a good idea.
I like it.
The, the, the auth stuff or the L4O2?
No, the L4O2.
Yeah.
Just, just the whole idea
of being able to, you know,
pay for content right in the app somehow.
Yeah.
I mean, I like it.
It just, we, we got to make, I think,
I think the problem right now is
lack of public documentation.
Yeah.
And that's why I met,
that's why I built that.
Yeah, you were at, yeah, I saw
that you were asking for that.
Yeah.
Cause we have, we just
have to be able to say,
go here and look at the
spec because the L2,
the L4O2 spec is not enough.
You have to have the, what
they're calling secure RSS and,
and I don't have a problem.
People are like, some people are
bothered by the name secure.
It doesn't bother me.
I mean, it's marketing sometimes.
I mean, we, we call it pod ping.
Yeah.
Really?
We, we, we, it's, it's
really a, um, you know,
blockchain message bus for
podcast notifications,
but that's too hard to say.
The domain name is unwieldy, you
know, pod ping is much easier.
Yes.
Secure RSS TM.
So I, I think, you know, I don't have
a problem with, with the name there.
Uh, but it's, you know,
all you're saying is it's just
a shorthand to say the ability
to buy paywalled content inside the feed.
And I don't have a problem with that.
Yeah.
Me neither.
I, I'm, I'm okay with all versions.
I know it works for me, but
I'm, I'm okay with, uh,
with all versions of monetization.
And there's probably a few versions
that haven't even been invented yet.
People come up with.
Oh yeah.
So, but value for value does seem to work,
whether you're subscribed
through Patreon or whatever.
I mean, that, that does seem to work.
I'm not sure if, uh, if the guy,
who are those guys making
a million dollars a month?
That's a lot of money.
A million dollars a month.
Are they on some kind of, uh, is
that like for exclusive content?
Because who are these guys?
Uh, I think it's, is it diary of a CEO?
I'm thinking.
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know.
Um, yeah, that was a power.
Joe Budden.
Joe.
Oh, Joe Budden.
That's right.
Oh, that's a, yeah.
Oh, he, he, he is the podfather.
They call him the podfather.
Is he called the podfather?
Yeah, I think so.
I, um, I'm going to be honest with you.
I don't know.
I had never heard of Joe
Budden until like a year ago.
It went, whenever he, he dropped,
everybody made a big deal
because he dropped his, because
he got out of his Spotify contract.
Right, right, right.
I'm like, who is this?
I'm like, I never even
heard this person's name.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I don't know who, who he is or how
he makes a million dollars a month.
Oh, good for him.
Yeah.
I mean, if, if, if it's,
if he's got it coming.
So how has it been getting back
to, uh, getting back to the.
Uh, the real world getting
back to the day job?
Uh, difficult.
I came back.
I had like 1700 emails in my
mailbox, in my inbox at work.
I was like, it was crushing.
Give me an example.
What were some of the, what were
some of the, the tickets about?
Um, a remote work, remote worker.
Uh, I, my left monitor
is blinking on and off.
I'm like, wait, didn't you have, didn't you
get to hire a guy who could do stuff for
that or was he gone too?
Oh no, no, it's, it, it's all, you,
that's the thing is when, you know,
when you're on a team or
whatever, you come back and you,
you have to sort through
what's already been
handled, what hasn't, you know, you
have to kind of like, so every,
every email is like
a triage process where you have to
go through and figure out, you know,
and you know, oh,
this, this contract is coming up for
renewal, you know, do you want to,
do you want this
new version of this software that
it's like, are we still using this?
It's just every, every email
has to be touched and triaged.
But I'm mostly, I got caught up with
that, uh, yesterday, uh, afternoon.
So that's, you know, that's
been good being, man,
being out in the wilderness was nice.
Amazing.
How long were you cut
off from any connection?
Uh, about six days.
Wow.
How did that feel?
Amazing.
I was like, oh, we got, we, we
got, we started in June Lake,
California and got on, we hiked
about nine and a half miles in to
connect with the John Muir trail.
Then, so then we, then we,
that was the first day.
And then the next day we
hiked over Donahue pass.
That was 11,000 feet.
There was, we had hiked through
some snow, came down into Yosemite,
into Yosemite wilderness.
And then, so then over the course of
the next four days, we hiked, um,
about 40 miles over to, um, Yosemite
Valley and landed right there.
It came out right there next
to Curry, Curry village.
Did you go into Curry village?
We did not.
We were going to go into
Curry village to get
a shower because somebody told us the, uh,
the, the door code for the showers.
Hey, if you just mentioned my name, we
would have gotten a shower and a coffee.
Hey, uh, do you know, Adam?
Yeah.
He's my bro.
Uh, we need, yeah.
We, how about that shower?
How about you hook us up with that
wifi password and the shower code?
You're too cheap to even go
get the shower code, Dave.
Really?
No, see, we, there was two parts.
This was our 25th wedding anniversary.
So there was two parts to this trip.
Oh, wait, there was, there was certainly
a luxurious suite part of the, uh, yes.
Oh yeah.
Okay.
Good, good, good.
There was the back country
part and the bougie part.
So we went back country to
bougie and like the first set,
the first six days were hiking
into Yosemite Valley.
That was about 60 miles.
And then the next three days were
lap of luxury at the Awani lodge.
Oh, nice, nice.
Yeah.
Good on you.
We got the suite, you
know, and all this stuff.
So yeah, we were, you know,
it was, it was a great trip.
It was, it was amazing.
Once you're, once you're out there
in the wilderness for a while,
like we got close enough to Yosemite
Valley, the lat on day
six in the afternoon.
And I was like, I wonder
if I have cell coverage.
And so I, I turned off
airplane mode cause I'd kept
it in an airplane mode to
keep the battery from dying.
Yeah.
So I took it off airplane mode and, um,
then like a hundred text
messages start flowing in.
And I'm like, no, no, put
it back on airplane mode.
Boop, boop, boop, boop, boop, boop.
I'm like, no, I don't want it.
I don't want it.
Server down, server down.
Yeah.
You know, you left without actually
giving me access to reboot anything.
I know.
I couldn't, I, I, I ran out of time.
And, and, you know, cause you
would give me a thing and I was,
and I tried to connect
it to my Linode account.
It didn't work.
And I said, well, try this.
And you just left.
And I'm like, well,
that's how God wants it.
So God will keep it running.
If not, oh well.
God or Dave.
God or Dave, whatever.
One or the other.
Like I worried about it the night before.
And then I was like, nah, it's fine.
Your stuff.
The one thing I can say about Dave
Jones, his stuff runs forever.
Stop.
You son of a bitch.
I invite the boogeyman in.
Don't you dare.
Hey, let's thank some people, Dave.
Okay.
All right.
You got some, uh, let's see.
I've got PayPal's and Boostergram.
Yeah.
I'll, uh, I'll do the stuff that
came in during the program,
during the board meeting
and a millennial was
listening and a millennial.
Butt got warm when I
was talking about him.
1776 sats.
Thanks for the shout out.
MMO is oftentimes described
as a boomerless no agenda.
Oh, I feel the love.
Just kidding.
All love.
Listen to MMO live Tuesdays,
530 on the no agenda stream.
Okay.
Uh, Martin Lindeskog,
1776 boost to Graham.
Freedom of expression.
I'm having a conversation with Grok
in Buy Me Coffee's Twitter X thread.
All right.
You need to step away.
What does that even mean?
Maybe I should ask about the
funding tag and podcasting 2.0.
Best, best premises, Martin.
P.S.
In Sweden, you can't decide regarding
the state-owned television and radio,
SVT, Sveriges Radio.
They get funded by a public service fee
levied as a tax on personal income.
Is it time for new pirate
radio and TV revolution?
You know, that's what podcasting is.
Uh, and Martin Lindeskog, another 1776.
Adam and Dave, I've missed you guys.
And now I hear you talk about poop.
Yes.
Today.
The poop app.
Go straight to the top of the leaderboard.
Today, I'm wearing podcasting
2.0 certified t-shirt.
Maybe I'll take a selfie and
post it on the interwebs.
I'm happy to be the number one super
fan on true fans of your podcast.
All the best from Martin.
Uh, Eric PP, 3333.
Welcome back, he says.
Uh, boosting in from,
uh, the, uh, boost CLI.
And we have, let me see, uh, pre-boost, uh,
triple, uh, four sevens from Dreb Scott.
Pre-boosting the boost boost
listening live via Cast-O-Matic.
Yes, indeed.
Came in from Cast-O-Matic.
Hoping you both had a
great and relaxing break.
Hashtag go podcasting.
And, uh, and I hit the delimiter.
That's it.
Uh, let's see.
Uh, we got, did we get, I'm
starting, I'm just hit me that
Cast-O-Matic didn't tell me
that the Bat-Sigma went out.
I sent, I'm pretty sure I sent it.
Yeah, yeah, it's there.
Okay.
It's there.
Don't scare me.
False alarm.
Yeah.
Uh, look who we got.
We got Buzzsprout came in
here with a thousand dollars.
Bam!
Shot collar, 20-inch blades on the Impala.
Thank you.
That keeps everything running here.
All, all boostsagrams, all
donations, everything matters.
It really evens out with some
of our, our hosting supporters.
Thank you, boys and girls.
And I went away and I came
back to a thousand dollars.
Uh, thank, uh, thanks guys.
Thanks, Kevin and Tom and the crew.
Uh, and then guess who else came in?
Who?
Ben and Alberto at RSS.com with $777.
Oh!
Baller!
Nice!
Shot collar, 20-inch blades on the Impala.
That is, uh, that is a,
that's, thank you so much.
I should go to the woods more often.
Go away!
Go away, Dave!
We do better when I leave.
Uh, Ben says, thank you for your
consistent work, clear thinking,
and steady commitment.
Here's to open podcasting
with RSS, the RSS.com team.
Thank you, RSS.com team.
Much appreciated.
Uh, my RSS.com shirt is, um,
the ones that Ben's wife made.
Oh, I, I don't have one.
Funny, you know.
On the, on the vinyl, uh, application
machine, it is, it is in bad shape.
It's peeling.
It's peeling after a couple of, uh,
washes, it starts to peel a bit.
I'm in need of a, of a
replacement RSS.com.
Is it kind of like the old, the old
t-shirt merch that you'd buy at, uh,
at the rock shows and it would be
just kind of almost like ironed on?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
It's like a, yeah, like
the vinyl cut thing.
Yeah.
Uh, we got, oh, we got a one off, I see,
one off from, uh, Shakozi, uh, Nagy,
uh, for $20 and there's no note.
Thank you, Shakozi.
And, uh, we got one from Francis
Navilla, Navillio, uh, for $10.
Thank you, Francis.
Appreciate that.
Uh, let's see.
Uh, what do we got?
We got, uh, Boostergrams somewhere in box.
Here we go.
Oh, here we go.
Uh, we got, uh, Bob Rathmel, 3,500 sats.
Hey, that sounds like a new one.
Bob Rathmel.
Never heard that name before.
You're defragmented, Bob.
Dribbs, kids, just defragmented you.
Uh, through Podverse, uh, 3,500 sats.
He says, uh, no need to read in the show.
Okay.
Well, you got it anyway.
You got it done.
I'm excited to hear all
the updates of your work.
I had some trouble updating
my Albi wallet to boost.
I'm sorry for the trouble, but you got it.
Seems like you got it.
Yeah.
I guess, uh, some of the
Albi wallets had problems.
Some of their, uh, inbound
liquidity failed or something.
Oh, oh yeah.
Um, I think Chad F mentioned that.
Yeah.
We had a, we had a node issue too.
Um, what, why did we have to reboot?
Because it's so fun to
reboot, uh, a Bitcoin node.
Hours.
Yeah.
Now, what happened was, uh, Randy
Black, he set up his own node.
He says, can you give me some liquidity?
And I kept trying and I
kept getting this error.
Like you can't open a channel unless
the node is fully synced to the chain.
And so I, of course, blamed Randy.
He said, yeah, you're crappy set up.
It's not synced to the chain.
Then I go into voltage because,
uh, we have, you know, our, our,
our big node is, uh, hosted by voltage.
All of your sats, everything is on that.
And we provide liquidity.
We have over a thousand
channels, by the way.
We have quite a lot of channels.
We have to have, we have to be in near
the top as far as channel count goes.
Channel count, maybe, but
not liquidity, but count.
No, not liquidity.
And so I kept getting this problem.
Then I go into voltage
into the dashboard and
our node is so big and so powerful that
the dashboard never shows anything properly,
but I see this flashing chain sync.
I'm like, Hey, so I ping Graham.
Now when you ping Graham on signal,
I don't care what time zone,
what day or night it is.
He is right away.
You see the three dots coming up.
What's going on?
Yeah.
It could be three o'clock in the morning.
Anywhere.
And he says, Oh, what version are you on?
I said, Oh yeah.
He says, no, you're on older version.
It's time to update.
I'm like, Oh, that means a reboot.
That means a reboot.
And there's two, two parts to it.
One, you got a reboot.
You know, you have to hit
update and it reboots.
It doesn't really give you a great
signal as to where it's, where it is,
but he's right there in the back.
And now I see it.
It's all going fine.
It's okay.
And then the system, cause Graham
has no access to the node.
The system will send me an email
saying you have to unlock the node.
And so you kind of like waiting on that.
And so that took several hours, but then it
worked out and I was able to give all of
this to say, I gave Randy
some inbound liquidity.
Long way to go to get Randy some inbound.
It took two guys, several hours,
but we got it done, Randy.
You got your liquidity.
This stuff's ready for prime time.
Are we on the latest L&D now?
Yeah, we are.
Okay.
Yeah.
Cause that, I mean, our node,
how long does it take to reboot?
Like seven hours?
No, no.
It went much faster.
I think it was three and a
half, three and a half hours.
It used to be like 10.
Yeah.
Oh, 10 or 12 hours is what it used to be.
Right now we're on, let me see.
I'll tell you what, what we're on.
Well, it's also a new
version of voltage cloud.
You know, so it had to be all
kinds of versions of stuff.
Let me just check, go to
infrastructure owner.
I'm the owner.
Yes.
Lightning nodes.
Okay.
We are on, let me see.
Why doesn't it tell me what the, hmm.
Oh, wait.
Node.
Info.
We're on 0.19.2-beta of LLD.
We're pretty, yeah, we're
pretty, we're pretty recent.
And I even.
I wonder if that has the SQL stuff in it.
Cause you know, they're
transitioning to a SQLite backend.
And I see that voltage, the voltage
version already has an update.
So I'm not going to do it.
Not today, Satan.
Wait till Randy needs more.
Yeah.
Well, it should work, I guess.
But yeah, if it has a SQL backend, then
that'll, I mean, your, your stats,
your daily stats email has
been broken for months.
Oh yeah.
It doesn't even work anymore.
I switched it over to just be like away from
the full report to just like a balance.
Yeah.
Bruce, the ugly quacking duck,
2222 through podcast guru says,
bravo team on the images tag.
Another win for podcasting.
Enjoy the tech discussion on this episode.
Thanks for all you do.
73s.
Kilo five, alpha, Charlie, Charlie.
Hey, look, look who we have here.
Who do we have here?
Dave?
Comic strip blogger, 12, nine,
one, five through fountain.
All right.
Comic strip blogger says,
howdy, Dave and Adam.
Are you missing Moe facts
with Adam Curry podcast?
I have a replacement for you.
So I have recommended this
podcast to Adam Curry's
keeper podcast before I knew that the
president of France is suing her.
So I recommend to her again here,
a political podcast called
Candace by Candace Owens.
I'm not sure that she is always
right, but she is very entertaining,
presents a strongly black American point
of view, akin to Moe from Moe facts.
I don't think it's
exactly the same as Moe.
Very different.
Quite, quite different.
I would say.
Yeah, it's quite different.
Thank you, CSB.
And do we have any, anything else?
Any monthlies?
Yeah, we got, we got a lot of monthlies.
Yeah.
This happens, what happens when
you're gone for half a month?
Yeah.
We got Podverse, $50.
Thank you, Podverse.
Basil Phillip, $25.
Christopher Horabarik, $10.
Mitch, that's Mitch Downey
over at Podverse, $10.
Terry Keller, $5.
Chris Cowan, $5.
Silicon Florist, $10.
Derek J. Visker, the best
name in podcasting, $21.
Paul Saltzman, $22.22.
Damon Kassajak, $15.
Jeremy Gerds, $5.
Michael Hall, $5.50.
New Media, that's Todd, $30.
Gene Liverman, $5.
Timothy Voice, $10.
Lauren Ball, $24.20.
Oystein Berra, $5.
Jorge Hernandez, $5.
Michael Goggin, $5.
Cohn Glotzbach, $5.
Christopher Reamer, $10.
James Sullivan, $10.
And Jordan Dunville, $10.
Wow.
Thank you all so much for
supporting the Podcast Index.
All funds go directly into the
Podcast Index Maintenance Fund.
Everything runs from that.
All servers, everything,
except the Mastodon.
I contribute the Mastodon out
of it because I love everybody.
And I have all the power.
You control.
I control everything.
The node, et cetera, everything.
We're so appreciative of that
because people are now building.
We're building.
We are indirectly benefiting.
People are building on Podcast Index.
It's a very important resource.
And all of your contributions
help keep that running.
Go to podcastindex.org.
Down at the bottom, there's
a red donate button.
If you hit on that, then you can send us
your fiat fund coupons through PayPal.
And, of course, you can always boost.
Boost the gram goes into the node.
And that just keeps getting more
valuable, which is, you know, we have,
Podcast Index indeed
has a Bitcoin treasury.
We are.
We are just like MicroStrategy.
Yes, that's right.
We are the sailors of podcasting.
Michael Saylor.
Yeah, we're going to, one day we're
going to leverage it for, to do a float.
Oh, yeah.
A SPAC.
A reverse merger.
Yeah, we're going to SPAC.
Do a SPAC.
Wrap it all up.
We're going to wrap everything
up into a SPAC, yeah.
So, you sent me an ISO.
Is that meant for the end of the show?
Or what was that meant for?
I was hoping you'd drop it in the
middle of our public radio discussion.
London Corning.
You're listening to a news bulletin read
in the overseas service of the BBC.
I actually forgot about it.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
Thanks for the pre-production.
As usual, anything we do before the
show is forgotten or just is no good.
That's how it always works.
It just falls on the floor.
We fly by the seat of our
pants every single time.
Brother Dave, good to have you back.
I apologize.
On Tuesday, we're going down to Florida.
I'm speaking in front of
the, what are they called?
The embassy churches.
I'm doing a talk with Pastor Jim.
What is it?
They're, so it's, it's a
group of churches and they
want to speak beyond the
walls of the sanctuary.
And so, Pastor Jimmy and I are
literally doing a talk on media,
the church and media.
Your, your, your wheelhouse.
Yes.
Two wheelhouses actually.
So, and that will be promoting
podcasting, obviously.
And since everyone, everybody who's,
who's in church has a podcast now,
they just don't know what
to do with them or, or how.
I think we, I think we probably have
to bring a lot of, by the way, a,
these would be good
customers for HLS video.
Ah, yeah.
And they need it because the, the
amount of times I hear the story.
Well, YouTube took down the sermon again.
You know, we got a strike, even though
they all pay royalties for, you know,
all kinds of music rights.
That's actually, that's not a bad idea.
I'll probably bring that up with them.
They probably don't know that you can do
video and that may be a good constituency
to push RSS-based video into reality.
So I will, I'll bring that up there.
Yeah, definitely.
And you're just going to be
going through support tickets?
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah, I'm hoping to work on, I need to,
I need to go answer this
post about secure RSS.
And, and, and purchasing
content and that kind of thing.
But I think I'm, I'm hopefully going to
work on the new aggregator this week.
Ooh.
A little bit.
Yeah.
I need, I need to get into that.
It's been sitting on
the table for too long.
So I need, I need to make
some progress on that.
Gathering dust.
Yeah, it's just sitting around.
Yeah, it's getting gooey.
It's that thick dust from the server room.
It's just gooey.
Blow it off.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right, brother.
Well, have yourself a great weekend, Dave.
And, uh.
Great, man.
You too.
Thank you very much.
Oystein Bergen is standing by.
He's coming up with, uh, his
mutton, mead, and music.
We'll be back here in two
weeks on Podcasting 2.0.
See you at boardroom.
You have been listening to Podcasting 2.0.
Visit podcastindex.org
for more information.
Go podcasting!
You do you, boo.